{
  "week0": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following allows us to identify objects and extract information?",
      "options": [
        "RFID",
        "Sensors",
        "Actuators",
        "IoT Nodes"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "RFID",
      "solution": "RFID Technology allows us to automatically identify and track tags that are attached to the objects. It extracts information from the tags through electromagnetic fields. See lecture 1 @ 12:57"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many layers does Zigbee consist of?",
      "options": [
        "1",
        "2",
        "3",
        "4"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "4",
      "solution": "Zigbee consists of 4 layers: Physical, Medium Access Control, Network, and Application. See lecture 48 @ 16:11"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a component of cloud computing?",
      "options": [
        "Clients",
        "Local Servers",
        "Services",
        "Applications"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Local Servers",
      "solution": "Cloud computing components include clients, services, applications, platform, storage, and infrastructure. See lecture 37 @ 23:29"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a distance measuring sensor module?",
      "options": [
        "DHT22",
        "HC-SR04",
        "TSL2591",
        "HC-SR505"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "HC-SR04",
      "solution": "HC-SR04 is the distance measuring module ultrasonic sensor, which measures the distance between 2cm~450cm. See lecture 3 @ 5:00"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a component in a typical sensor network?",
      "options": [
        "Sink",
        "Gateway",
        "Router",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "A typical sensor network comprises of sensor nodes, routers, gateway, and sink."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following sensors are responsible for measuring orientation and angular velocity?",
      "options": [
        "Accelerometer",
        "GPS",
        "Temperature",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "None of these",
      "solution": "A gyroscope is responsible for measuring orientation and angular velocity. See lecture 59 @ 15:41"
    },
    {
      "question": "\"ISA 100.11A\" is a wireless networking technology standard. ISA stands for",
      "options": [
        "International Society of Automation",
        "International Society of Advancement",
        "Industrial Society of Automation",
        "Industrial Society of Advancement"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "International Society of Automation",
      "solution": "ISA100.11a is a wireless networking technology standard developed by the International Society of Automation (ISA). See lecture 13@ 15:55"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a difference between traditional data center and cloud computing?",
      "options": [
        "Scalability",
        "Flexibility",
        "Elasticity",
        "Storage"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Storage",
      "solution": "Major differences between traditional data center and cloud computing include scalability, flexibility, elasticity, automation, running costs, and security. See lecture 39 @ 11:02"
    },
    {
      "question": "Smart grid is also known as the energy internet.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "Smart grid is also known as the energy internet. See lecture 51 @ 7:51"
    },
    {
      "question": "Can a point of node failure result in the partition of the network in the stationary sensor network?",
      "options": [
        "Yes",
        "No"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Yes",
      "solution": "If there is a failure in the stationary sensor network then it is likely that the point of failure can partition the network into two or more fragments. See lecture 18 @ 01:10"
    }
  ],
  "week1": [
    {
      "question": "What is the full form of IoT?",
      "options": [
        "Internet of Tasks",
        "Internet of Things",
        "Internet of Tasks",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Internet of Things",
      "solution": "The full form of IoT is \"Internet of Things\". See lecture 1 (Introduction to IoT - Part I) @ 1:30"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following technologies have unified and has resulted in the evolution of IoT?",
      "options": [
        "Low-power embedded systems",
        "Cloud Computing",
        "Machine Learning",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Unification of technologies which has resulted in the advancement of IoT are a. Low-power embedded systems b. Cloud Computing c. Big Data d. Machine Learning e. Networking. See lecture 1 (Introduction to IoT - Part I) @ 5:54"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are the enablers of IoT?",
      "options": [
        "RFID",
        "Nanotechnology",
        "Sensors",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "The enables of IoT are - a. RFID b. Nanotechnology c. Sensors d. Smart Networks. See lecture 2 (Introduction to IoT - Part I) @ 12:50"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is/are a function of an IoT Gateway?",
      "options": [
        "Connects the IoT LAN to a WAN",
        "Can implement several LAN and WAN",
        "Forwards packets between LAN and WAN on the IP layer",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "The functionalities of an IoT Gateway are a. Connects the IoT LAN to a WAN b. Can implement several LAN and WAN c. Forwards packets between LAN and WAN on the IP layer. See lecture 2 (Introduction to IoT - Part - II) @ 3:09"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is True or False. Statement: \"The same address of an IoT device may be repeated in the domain of another gateway. The gateway has a unique network prefix, which can be used to identify them globally.\"",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "The same address of an IoT device may be repeated in the domain of another gateway. The gateway has a unique network prefix, which can be used to identify them globally. See lecture 2 (Introduction to IoT - Part II) @ 07:00"
    },
    {
      "question": "In ___ a node/network is connected to multiple networks for improved reliability.",
      "options": [
        "Transparent roaming",
        "Multi-homing",
        "None of these",
        "Both (a) and (b)"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Multi-homing",
      "solution": "In multi-homing, a node/network is connected to multiple networks for improved reliability. See lecture 2 (Introduction to IoT - Part II) @ 15:22"
    },
    {
      "question": "The IPv4 notation uses ___ number of bits to represent an address.",
      "options": [
        "33",
        "32",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "32",
      "solution": "The IPv4 notation uses 32 bits to represent an address. See lecture 2 (Introduction to IoT - Part - II) @ 16:33"
    },
    {
      "question": "The \"Source Address\" field in the IPv6 header is of ___ bits in length.",
      "options": [
        "32",
        "64",
        "128",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "128",
      "solution": "The IPv6 header uses 128 bits to represent the \"Source Address\". See lecture 2 (Introduction to IoT - Part - II) @ 18:03"
    },
    {
      "question": "A device which detects or measures a physical property and records, indicates, or otherwise responds to it is called ___?",
      "options": [
        "A sensor",
        "An actuator",
        "A Transducer",
        "A processor"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "A sensor",
      "solution": "A device which detects or measures a physical property and records, indicates, or otherwise responds to it is called a sensor. See lecture 3 (Sensing) @ 03:28"
    },
    {
      "question": "A microphone is an example of an",
      "options": [
        "Input device and actuator",
        "Only actuator",
        "Only Transducer",
        "Input device and transducer"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Input device and transducer",
      "solution": "A microphone is an example of an input device and transducer. See lecture 3 (Sensing) @ 10:31"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is True or False. Statement: A sensor is only sensitive to the measured property for which it has been made (e.g., A temperature sensor senses the ambient temperature of a room.)",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "A sensor is only sensitive to the measured property (e.g., A temperature sensor senses the ambient temperature of a room.) See lecture 3 (Sensing) @ 12:11"
    },
    {
      "question": "Based on the data type, sensors are classified as",
      "options": [
        "Only scalar",
        "Only vector",
        "Scalar and Vector/Multimedia",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Scalar and Vector/Multimedia",
      "solution": "Based on the data type, sensors are classified as Scalar and Vector/Multimedia. See lecture 3 (Sensing) @ 13:05"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is True or False. Statement: The more the resolution of a sensor, the less accurate its precision.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "The more the resolution of a sensor, the more accurate its precision. See lecture 3 (Sensing) @ 12:46"
    },
    {
      "question": "The sensitivity of a sensor under real conditions may differ from the value specified. This is called",
      "options": [
        "Physical error",
        "Sensitivity error",
        "Rounding error",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Sensitivity error",
      "solution": "The sensitivity of a sensor under real conditions may differ from the value specified. See lecture 3 (Sensitivity error) @ 20:56"
    },
    {
      "question": "A sensor node is made up of which of the following?",
      "options": [
        "Sensor/Sensing units",
        "A processing unit",
        "A power unit",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "A sensor node is made up of a combination of sensor/sensors, a processor unit, a radio unit, and a power unit. See Page number 101, Chapter 5, Book Introduction to IoT..."
    }
  ],
  "week2": [
    {
      "question": "The full form of MQTT is",
      "options": [
        "Message Query Telemetry Transport",
        "Message Queue Telemetry Transport",
        "Message Queue Telemedicine Transport",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Message Queue Telemetry Transport",
      "solution": "The full form of MQTT is Message Queue Telemetry Transport. See lecture 6 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part II) @ 01:51"
    },
    {
      "question": "In MQTT, a ___ controls the publish-subscribe messaging pattern.",
      "options": [
        "Message Broker",
        "Publishers",
        "Subscribers",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Message Broker",
      "solution": "In MQTT, a message broker controls the publish-subscribe messaging pattern. See lecture 6 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part II) @ 03:33"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a Data Protocol in IoT?",
      "options": [
        "MQTT",
        "CoAP",
        "Websocket",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "None of these",
      "solution": "The data protocols in IoT are - a) MQTT b) COAP c) AMQP d) Websocket. See lecture 6 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part II) @ 01:16"
    },
    {
      "question": "In MQTT for IoT, the Publishers are",
      "options": [
        "Lightweight sensors",
        "Actuators",
        "Processing units",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Lightweight sensors",
      "solution": "In MQTT, the Publishers are lightweight sensors. See lecture 6 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part II) @ 04:49"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a method in MQTT?",
      "options": [
        "Break",
        "Connect",
        "Disconnect",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Break",
      "solution": "Following are the methods in MQTT - a. Connect b. Disconnect c. Subscribe d. Unsubscribe e. Publish. See lecture 6 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part II) @ 06:18"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following protocols in IoT have been designed for Machine to Machine (M2M) applications such as smart energy and building automation?",
      "options": [
        "MQTT",
        "CoAP",
        "Websocket",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "CoAP",
      "solution": "CoAP has been designed for Machine to Machine (M2M) applications such as smart energy and building automation. See lecture 7 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part III) @ 00:41"
    },
    {
      "question": "Similar to HTTP, CoAP utilizes which of the following for operation?",
      "options": [
        "GET",
        "PUT",
        "PUSH",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Similar to HTTP, COAP utilizes GET, PUT, PUSH, DELETE message requests to retrieve, create, update, and delete, respectively. See lecture 7 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part III) @ 08:24"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the full form of XMPP in IoT?",
      "options": [
        "Extensible Markup Page Processing",
        "Extensible Messaging and Presence Protocol",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "Neither (a) nor (b)"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Extensible Messaging and Presence Protocol",
      "solution": "XMPP stands for Extensible Messaging and Presence Protocol. See lecture 7 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part III) @ 11:58"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement if True or False. Statement: XMPP is an open standard protocol.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "XMPP is an open standard protocol. See lecture 7 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part III) @ 11:58"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the full form AMQP in context of IoT protocol?",
      "options": [
        "Another Message Queuing Protocol",
        "Anchored Message Queuing Protocol",
        "Advanced Message Queuing Protocol",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Advanced Message Queuing Protocol",
      "solution": "AMQP stands for Advanced Message Queuing Protocol. See lecture 8 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part IV) @ 0:41"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the basic unit of data in the AMQP protocol?",
      "options": [
        "Chunk",
        "Byte",
        "Frame",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Frame",
      "solution": "In AMQP, the basic unit of data is called a frame. See lecture 8 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part IV) @ 0:41"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is/are exchange types in AMQP?",
      "options": [
        "Direct",
        "Fan-out",
        "Topic",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "The AMQP exchange types are a) Direct b) Fan-out c) Topic d) Header. See lecture 8 (Basics of IoT Networking - Part IV) @ 08:56"
    },
    {
      "question": "IoT networks can be classified in which of the following type/types?",
      "options": [
        "Non-Beacon Enabled",
        "Beacon Enabled",
        "None of these",
        "Both (a) and (b)"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Both (a) and (b)",
      "solution": "The IoT networks can be classified into two types such as i. Non-Beacon Enabled ii. Beacon Enabled. See lecture 9 (Connectivity Technologies - Part-I) @ 10:19"
    },
    {
      "question": "The OSI model has ___ layers.",
      "options": [
        "6",
        "7",
        "4",
        "8"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "7",
      "solution": "The OSI model is a conceptual framework that divides any networked communication system into seven layers. See Page number - 10, Chapter 1, Book - Introduction to IoT..."
    },
    {
      "question": "The \"Destination Address\" in the IPv4 packet represents which of the following?",
      "options": [
        "The destination node address of the packet",
        "The intermediate hop in the network",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "The destination node address of the packet",
      "solution": "The \"Destination Address\" in the IPv4 packet represents the address of the destination node in the network. See Page number 18, Chapter 1, Book - Introduction to IoT..."
    }
  ],
  "week3": [
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: There is no network layer in Wired HART",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "There is no network layer in Wired HART. See lecture 11 (Connectivity Technologies-III) @ 05:22"
    },
    {
      "question": "HART operates only in ___ GHz ISM band.",
      "options": [
        "2.4",
        "4.8",
        "4.9",
        "4.4"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2.4",
      "solution": "HART operates only in 2.4 GHz ISM band. See lecture 11 (Connectivity Technologies-III) @ 05:43"
    },
    {
      "question": "Super-frames in HART consist of grouped ___ wide timeslots.",
      "options": [
        "10ms",
        "20ms",
        "55ms",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "10ms",
      "solution": "Super-frames in HART consist of grouped 10ms wide timeslots. See lecture 11 (Connectivity Technologies-III) @ 07:05"
    },
    {
      "question": "The process of identifying channels consistently affected by interference and removing them from use is known as",
      "options": [
        "Channel hopping",
        "Channel aggregating",
        "Frequency aggregating",
        "Channel blacklisting"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Channel blacklisting",
      "solution": "Channel Blacklisting identifies channels consistently affected by interference and removes them from use. See lecture 11 (Connectivity Technologies-III) @ 07:30"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is True or False. Statement: Each node is supervised by the application manager and it guides them on when and where to send packets.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "The Network manager supervises each node in the network and guides them on when and where to send packets. See lecture 11 (Connectivity Technologies-III) @ 12:14"
    },
    {
      "question": "FeliCa is commonly found in which country?",
      "options": [
        "Japan",
        "India",
        "USA",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Japan",
      "solution": "FeliCa is commonly found in Japan. See lecture 11 (Connectivity Technologies-III) @ 17:52"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following state is true or false. Statement: NFC tags found in supermarket products are examples of passive NFC.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "Passive NFC tags found in supermarket products are examples of passive NFC. See lecture 11 (Connectivity Technologies-III) @ 18:47"
    },
    {
      "question": "Active NFC devices are able to ___?",
      "options": [
        "transmit information",
        "collect information",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Both (a) and (b)",
      "solution": "Active NFC devices are able to collect as well as transmit information. See lecture 11 (Connectivity Technologies-III) @ 18:52"
    },
    {
      "question": "A ___ in NFC emits a small electric current which creates a magnetic field that in turn bridges the physical space between the devices.",
      "options": [
        "reader",
        "writer",
        "destroyer",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "reader",
      "solution": "A reader in NFC emits a small electric current which creates a magnetic field that in turn bridges the physical space between the devices. See lecture 11 (Connectivity Technologies-III) @ 20:31"
    },
    {
      "question": "Bluetooth technology is based on",
      "options": [
        "WiFi",
        "LoRa",
        "Ad-hoc technology",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Ad-hoc technology",
      "solution": "Bluetooth technology is based on Ad-hoc technology. See lecture 12 (Connectivity Technologies-IV) @ 02:30"
    },
    {
      "question": "Bluetooth technology operates in the unlicensed industrial, scientific and medical (ISM) band at ___ to ___ GHz.",
      "options": [
        "3.2, 5.6",
        "2.4, 2.485",
        "5.0, 5.89",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "2.4, 2.485",
      "solution": "Bluetooth technology operates in the unlicensed industrial, scientific and medical (ISM) band at 2.4 to 2.485 GHz. See lecture 12 (Connectivity Technologies-IV) @ 04:39"
    },
    {
      "question": "Z-wave operates at ___ MHz in the US and ___ MHz in Europe.",
      "options": [
        "1008, 989",
        "908.42, 868.42",
        "767.56, 855.28",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "908.42, 868.42",
      "solution": "Z-wave operates at 908.42 MHz in the US and 868.42 MHz in Europe. See lecture 13 (Connectivity Technologies-V) @ 3:40"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: Sensor nodes have limited battery life.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "Sensors nodes have limited battery life. See lecture 14 (Sensor Networks-I) @ 13:15"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: The Link Manager Protocol in Bluetooth manages the establishment, authentication, link configuration.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "The Link Manager Protocol in Bluetooth manages the establishment, authentication, link configuration. See Page number 157, Chapter 7, Book - Introduction to IoT..."
    },
    {
      "question": "Zigbee commonly uses ___ data rate.",
      "options": [
        "250 kbps",
        "250 Mbps",
        "260 kbps",
        "260 Mbps"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "250 kbps",
      "solution": "Zigbee commonly uses 250 kbps data rate. See Page number-131, Chapter - 7, Book - Introduction to IoT..."
    }
  ],
  "week4": [
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: Coverage in WSN is defined as the area-of-interest that is covered satisfactorily.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "Coverage in WSN is defined as the area-of-interest that is covered satisfactorily. See lecture 17 (Sensor Networks-IV) @ 01:44"
    },
    {
      "question": "If transmission range >= 2 * sensing range,",
      "options": [
        "Coverage implies connectivity",
        "Coverage implies greater coverage",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Coverage implies connectivity",
      "solution": "If transmission range >= 2* sensing range, coverage implies connectivity. See lecture 17 (Sensor Networks-IV) @ 04:14"
    },
    {
      "question": "Forest fire monitoring in WSN is an example of which type of reporting?",
      "options": [
        "Event driven",
        "On-demand",
        "Scattered",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Event driven",
      "solution": "Forest fire monitoring in WSN is an example of event driven reporting. See lecture 17 (Sensor Networks-IV) @ 08:13"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: Objective of coverage in WSN is to use minimum number of sensors and maximize network lifetime.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "The objective of coverage in WSN is to use minimum number of sensors and maximize the network lifetime. See lecture 17 (Sensor Networks-IV) @ 08:47"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the full form of AUV in the context of mobile wireless sensor networks?",
      "options": [
        "Aerial and Underwater Vehicle",
        "Ambient and Underprivileged Vehicle",
        "Autonomous Underwater Vehicle",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Autonomous Underwater Vehicle",
      "solution": "The full form of AUV is Autonomous Underwater Vehicle. See lecture 18 (Sensor Networks-V) @ 07:56"
    },
    {
      "question": "In mobile wireless sensor networks, the sensor nodes are capable of ___ and measuring the condition of their surrounding environments.",
      "options": [
        "collaborating with one another",
        "destroying one another",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "collaborating with one another",
      "solution": "In mobile wireless sensor networks, the sensor nodes are capable of collaborating with one another and measuring the condition of their surrounding environments. See lecture 18 (Sensor Networks-V) @ 04:56"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: In mobile sensor networks, the sensor nodes come in close proximity of sink and deliver the data.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "In mobile sensor networks, the sensor nodes come in close proximity of sink and deliver the data. See lecture 18 (Sensor Networks-V) @ 06:19"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is/are a challenge/challenges in Human-centric Sensing?",
      "options": [
        "Energy of devices",
        "Participant selection",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Both (a) and (b)",
      "solution": "The following are the challenges in human-centric sensing - a. Energy of devices b. Participant selection c. Privacy of users. See lecture 18 (Sensor Networks-V) @ 12:45"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is/are a feature/features of UAV networks?",
      "options": [
        "Mesh or star networks",
        "Multi-tasking",
        "Large coverage area",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "The following are the features of UAV networks - d. Mesh or star networks e. Multi-tasking f. Large coverage area. See lecture 19 (UAV Networks) @ 02:43"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: Frequently change in network topology is a benefit of UAV networks.",
      "options": [
        "False",
        "True"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "Frequently change in network topology an issue of UAV networks. See lecture 19 (UAV Networks) @ 05:29"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a feature of multi-UAV system?",
      "options": [
        "Low failures",
        "High scalability",
        "Low survivability",
        "High cost"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Low survivability",
      "solution": "Following are some of the features of multi-UAV system - a. Low failures b. High scalability c. High survivability d. High cost. See lecture 19 (UAV Networks) @ 07:53"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: M2M communications are free of any human intervention.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "M2M communications are free of any human intervention. See lecture 20 (Machine to Machine Communication) @ 05:44"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT an M2M node type?",
      "options": [
        "Secure End Node",
        "High End Node",
        "Low End Mode",
        "Mid End Node"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Secure End Node",
      "solution": "M2M node types are as follows - a. Low End Node b. Mid End Node c. High End Node. See lecture 20 (Machine to Machine Communication) @ 10:43"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the full form of M2SP in the context of Machine-to-Machine Communication?",
      "options": [
        "M2M Service Platform",
        "M2M Session Packet",
        "M2M Secure Packaging",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "M2M Service Platform",
      "solution": "M2SP stands for M2M Service Platform. See lecture 20 (Machine to Machine Communication) @ 16:31"
    },
    {
      "question": "The ___ provides integrated services based on device collected data-sets.",
      "options": [
        "M2M Application Platform",
        "M2M Service Platform",
        "M2M Hardware Platform",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "M2M Application Platform",
      "solution": "The M2M Application Platform provides integrated services based on device collected data-sets. See lecture 20 (Machine to Machine Communication) @ 18:00"
    }
  ],
  "week5": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is/are current challenge/challenges in IoT?",
      "options": [
        "Large scale of co-operation",
        "Global heterogeneity",
        "Unknown IoT device configuration",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Current challenges in IoT are a. Large scale of co-operation b. Global heterogeneity c. Unknown IoT device configuration d. Semantic conflicts. See lecture 21 (Interoperability in Internet of Things) @ 03:41."
    },
    {
      "question": "When two IoT devices wish to communicate, semantic conflict in such a scenario in IoT interoperability refers to",
      "options": [
        "Two devices built by the same manufacturer",
        "Two devices having different processing and business logic",
        "Two devices sensing the same physical parameter",
        "Two devices having different deployment location"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Two devices having different processing and business logic",
      "solution": "Semantic conflict refers to when different IoT devices have different processing and business execution logic. Refer Lecture 21@5:32"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following issues needs to be addressed while solving user interoperability?",
      "options": [
        "Device characterization and identification",
        "Syntactic interoperability",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Both (a) and (b)",
      "solution": "All of the options given should be addressed while solving user interoperability issues. Refer Lecture 21@15:16."
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: UMB core interoperability component is responsible for converting physical devices into virtually abstracted ones.",
      "options": [
        "False",
        "True"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "UMB-A is responsible for converting physical devices into virtually abstracted ones. (Please refer Lecture 21 @27:16)"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the full form of UMB in IoT interoperability?",
      "options": [
        "Universal Middleware Bridge",
        "Universal Main Bridge",
        "Universal Main Bracket",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Universal Middleware Bridge",
      "solution": "UMB stands for Universal Middleware Bridge. Refer Lecture 21@22:16."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a function available in the Servo library for Arduino ?",
      "options": [
        "kill()",
        "destroy()",
        "burn()",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "The following are NOT functions of the Servo library for Arduino a. kill() b. destroy() c. burn(). The Refer Lecture 25@18:08."
    },
    {
      "question": "Arduino UNO Board is open source?",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "An Arduino UNO board is an open source electronic programmable board. Refer Lecture 22@05:21."
    },
    {
      "question": "Arduino Uno board accepts which type of input/inputs?",
      "options": [
        "Analog",
        "Digital",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Both (a) and (b)",
      "solution": "Arduino UNO board accepts analog and digital signals as input. Refer Lecture 22@05:21"
    },
    {
      "question": "Arduino boards are based on which of the following microcontroller/microcontrollers.",
      "options": [
        "ATMEGA328",
        "ATMEGA32u4",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Both (a) and (b)",
      "solution": "Arduino board are based on the following microcontrollers - a. ATMEGA328 b. ATMEGA32u4 c. ATMEGA2560 d. AT91SAM3X8E. Refer Lecture 22@06:20"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the clock speed of the Arduino Uno board?",
      "options": [
        "16MHz",
        "17MHz",
        "8MHz",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "16MHz",
      "solution": "The clock speed of Arduino Uno board is 16MHz. Refer Lecture 22 @ 07:13."
    },
    {
      "question": "What must be inserted in the place of ?? within the second pinMode() function in void setup()? ... pinMode(g,?? ); ...",
      "options": [
        "INPUT",
        "OUTPUT",
        "None of these",
        "Anyone of these is okay"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "OUTPUT",
      "solution": "Since pin 'g' is writing digital values, it is required to set in OUTPUT mode. Refer Lecture 22-23."
    },
    {
      "question": "The \"Verify\" option in the Arduino IDE checks the code for",
      "options": [
        "Compilation errors",
        "Improper hardware connection",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Compilation errors",
      "solution": "The \"Verify\" option in the Arduino IDE checks the code for compilation errors. Refer Lecture 24."
    },
    {
      "question": "How many pins does the DHT Digital Humidity and Temperature sensor have?",
      "options": [
        "2",
        "3",
        "4",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "4",
      "solution": "DHT Digital Humidity and Temperature sensor has 4 pins. See lecture 24 @ 03:23"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the function of the delay() function in an Arduino program?",
      "options": [
        "Initializes a sensor",
        "Introduces a delay for the specified time",
        "Stores the sensor value",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Introduces a delay for the specified time",
      "solution": "The delay() function introduces a delay in the operation of the microcontroller for the specified duration. See lecture 24 @13:51"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the following code snippet do? Servo myservo;",
      "options": [
        "Creates a variable to store the sensor value",
        "Instructs the sensor to sense data",
        "Creates an instance of servo to use it in the Arduino sketch",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Creates an instance of servo to use it in the Arduino sketch",
      "solution": "The code snipped \"Servo myservo;\" creates an instance of servo to use in the Arduino sketch. Refer Lecture 25 @5:32"
    }
  ],
  "week6": [
    {
      "question": "Python can only be used to build small applications.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "With open-source nature, python forms a strong backbone to build large applications. (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON PROGRAMMING- I @ 3:46)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a Python IDE?",
      "options": [
        "Spyder",
        "PyCharm",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "None of these",
      "solution": "Spyder and PyCharm are examples of Python IDE. (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON PROGRAMMING- I @ 05:12)"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: To indicate different blocks of code, python follows rigid indention.",
      "options": [
        "False",
        "True"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "To indicate different blocks of code, python follows rigid indention (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON PROGRAMMING- I @ 07:25)."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a data-type in Python?",
      "options": [
        "List",
        "Branch",
        "Tuple",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Branch",
      "solution": "The data-types in python are a. List b. Tuple c. Dictionary (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON PROGRAMMING- I @ 15:20)."
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: Python allows us to read and write files.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "Python allows us to read and write files. (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON PROGRAMMING- II @ 01:17)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT a mode to open a file?",
      "options": [
        "Read mode",
        "Write mode",
        "Append mode",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "None of these",
      "solution": "The four basic modes to open a file in python are a. Read mode b. Write mode c. Append mode d. Both read and write mode (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON PROGRAMMING- II @ 03:00)"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following command to install the PIL library in Linux is correct or not. sudo pip install pillow",
      "options": [
        "Correct",
        "Incorrect"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Correct",
      "solution": "The command to install the PIL library is sudo pip install pillow. (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON PROGRAMMING- II @ 17:40)"
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is correct for creating a socket 's' in python. s = socket.socket(socket_family, socket_type, protocol=0)",
      "options": [
        "Correct",
        "Incorrect"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Correct",
      "solution": "The statement s = socket.socket(socket_family, socket_type, protocol=0) creates a socket in python. (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON PROGRAMMING- II @24:27)."
    },
    {
      "question": "What is a Raspberry Pi?",
      "options": [
        "A computer on your palm",
        "Single board computer",
        "Low cost",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Raspberry pi is a. A computer on your palm b. Single board computer c. Low cost d. Easy to access (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO RASPBERRY PI-I @05:00)."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are required for a basic set up of Raspberry Pi?",
      "options": [
        "Monitor",
        "Keyboard",
        "Mouse",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "The following are required for a basic set up of Raspberry Pi - a. Monitor b. Keyboard c. Mouse. See lecture INTRODUCTION TO RASPBERRY PI-I @ 11:33"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following keyboard key combination writes (i.e saves) the code to the file in nano editor ?",
      "options": [
        "Ctrl+O",
        "Ctrl+X",
        "Both (a) and (b)",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Ctrl+O",
      "solution": "Ctrl+O writes the code to the file in nano editor. See lecture INTRODUCTION TO RASPBERRY PI-II @ 10:44"
    },
    {
      "question": "A relay module for Raspberry Pi has how many terminals ?",
      "options": [
        "3",
        "2",
        "4",
        "5"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "3",
      "solution": "A relay module for Raspberry Pi has 3 terminals. See lecture IMPLEMENTATION OF IOT WITH RASPBERRY PI-I @ 06:01."
    },
    {
      "question": "State whether the following statement is true or false. Statement: Adafruit provides a library to work with the DHT22 sensor.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "Adafruit provides a library to work with the DHT22 sensor. See lecture IMPLEMENTATION OF IOT WITH RASPBERRY PI-I @ 09:19"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the function of the close() function in python programming while handling files.",
      "options": [
        "This function does not exist in python",
        "It closes the current connection to the file and ensures that the file is free to use for other resources",
        "None of these",
        "Both (a) and (b)"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "It closes the current connection to the file and ensures that the file is free to use for other resources",
      "solution": "The close() function in python ensures that the file is free to use for other resources. (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON PROGRAMMING-II @ 4:44)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is the Raspbian image found?",
      "options": [
        "It is not available on the Internet",
        "It is available as image file from the Raspberry Pi official website",
        "It can only be purchased from offline vendor",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "It is available as image file from the Raspberry Pi official website",
      "solution": "Raspbian image can be downloaded from the Raspberry Pi official website. (Please refer to lecture INTRODUCTION TO RASPBERYY PI-I @ 12:32)"
    }
  ],
  "week7": [
    {
      "question": "DHT Sensor refers to Digital Humidity and Temperature Sensor.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "DHT Sensor refers to Digital Humidity and Temperature Sensor. (Please refer to lecture Implementation of IoT with Raspberry Pi- II @ 3:28)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blanks. ___ is a python library used for plotting the data in 2D.",
      "options": [
        "List",
        "Numpy",
        "Pandas",
        "Matplotlib"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Matplotlib",
      "solution": "Matplotlib is a python library used for plotting the data in 2D. (Please refer to lecture Implementation of IoT with Raspberry Pi- III @ 12:13)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blanks. ___ makes a scatter plot of the given points.",
      "options": [
        "ion()",
        "figure()",
        "Scatter()",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Scatter()",
      "solution": "Scatter() makes a scatter plot of the given points. (Please refer to lecture Implementation of IoT with Raspberry Pi- III @ 23:25)."
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the two main challenges of SDN?",
      "options": [
        "File placement and Node placement",
        "Rule placement and Controller placement",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Rule placement and Controller placement",
      "solution": "Rule placement and Controller placement are the two main challenges of SDN. (Please refer to lecture Software Defined Networking- Part-I @ 16:49)"
    },
    {
      "question": "In soft-timeout, all the rules are deleted from the switch.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "In soft-timeout, if no flow is received associated with a rule for a particular time, the rule is deleted. In hard-timeout, all rules are deleted from the switch. (Please refer to lecture Software Defined Networking- Part-I @ 24:57)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a component of SDN?",
      "options": [
        "Hardware switches",
        "Flow-rules",
        "None of these",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Hardware switches and Flow rules are both the components of SDN. (Please refer to lecture Software Def ined Networking- Part-I @ 15.47)"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is introduced if a controller is down in SDN?",
      "options": [
        "Backup controller",
        "Intro controller",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Backup controller",
      "solution": "Backup controller is introduced if a controller is down in SDN. (Please refer to lecture Software Defined Networking- Part- II @ 8:29)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Southbound API is used to communicate between control layer and application layer.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "Southbound API is used to communicate between control layer and infrastructure layer. (Please refer to lecture 34 Software Defined Networking- Part-II @1:41)."
    },
    {
      "question": "SDN is OpenFlow.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "SDN is not OpenFlow. It is a technology/concept. (Please refer to lecture 33 Software Defined Networking- Part-I @25:55)."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following forwards the sensed data based on the ID of the source node?",
      "options": [
        "Value-centric data forwarding",
        "ID-centric data forwarding",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "ID-centric data forwarding",
      "solution": "ID-centric data forwarding forwards the sensed data based on the ID of the source node. See lecture 35 @ 9:50"
    },
    {
      "question": "Does integrating SDN in IoT provide intelligent routing decisions?",
      "options": [
        "Yes",
        "No"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Yes",
      "solution": "Integrating SDN in IoT provides intelligent routing decisions. See lecture 35 @ 17:25"
    },
    {
      "question": "Are Indigo and LINC Open source?",
      "options": [
        "Yes",
        "No"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Yes",
      "solution": "Indigo and LINC are both open source. See lecture 33@ 26:43."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is used to communicate among multiple controllers in the control layer?",
      "options": [
        "East-Westbound APIS",
        "Northbound APIs",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "East-Westbound APIS",
      "solution": "East-Westbound APIs are used to communicate among multiple controllers in the control layer. See lecture 34 @ 02:39"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many requests can a controller handle through a single thread?",
      "options": [
        "200/sec",
        "50/sec",
        "None of these",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "200/sec",
      "solution": "A controller can handle 200 requests in a second through a single thread. (Please refer to lecture 34@ 3:47)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Size of the ternary content-addressable memory is not limited at the switches.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "Size of the ternary content-addressable memory is limited at the switches (Please refer to lecture 33 @ 20:41)"
    }
  ],
  "week8": [
    {
      "question": "Which of these is used for efficient base-station coordination for addressing inter-cell interference?",
      "options": [
        "Path management",
        "Routing protocols",
        "Flow-table paradigm",
        "Logically centralized control"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Logically centralized control",
      "solution": "Logically centralized control is used for efficient base-station coordination for addressing inter-cell interference (Please refer Lecture 36@3:02)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these takes last k-th location instances to predict the next location in Mobi-Flow?",
      "options": [
        "Order-K Markov predictor",
        "Flow-rule placement",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Order-K Markov predictor",
      "solution": "Order-K Markov predictor takes last k-th location instances to predict the next location in Mobi-Flow. (Please refer Lecture 36@15:52)"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the two components of ODIN?",
      "options": [
        "Odin server and agent",
        "Odin server and client",
        "Odin agent and master",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Odin agent and master",
      "solution": "Odin agent and master are the two components of ODIN. (Please refer Lecture 36@10:16)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is placed to deal with mice-flows?",
      "options": [
        "Flow rules",
        "Exact rules",
        "Match rules",
        "Wild card rules"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Wild card rules",
      "solution": "Wild card rules can be placed to deal with mice-flows. (Please refer Lecture 36 @18:23)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank. ___ refers to heterogeneous computing nodes distributed over a wide area to perform very large tasks.",
      "options": [
        "Cluster Computing",
        "Utility Computing",
        "Grid Computing",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Grid Computing",
      "solution": "Grid Computing refers to heterogeneous computing nodes distributed over a wide area to perform very large tasks. (Please refer Lecture 37 @6:48)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a property of cloud computing?",
      "options": [
        "On-demand network access",
        "High level generalization of computation",
        "On-demand services",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "On-demand network access, high level generalization of computation and on-demand services are some of the properties of cloud computing. (Please refer Lecture 37@12:43)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements are true about the different types of cloud? Statement I: Inter-cloud is a global cloud of clouds. Statement II: Volunteer cloud is a type of distributed cloud. Statement III: Public cloud has low security.",
      "options": [
        "Statements I and II",
        "Statements I and III",
        "Statements II and III",
        "Statement I, II and III"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Statement I, II and III",
      "solution": "All the three statements are correct for the cloud. Inter-cloud is a global cloud of clouds. Volunteer cloud is a type of distributed cloud. And also Public cloud has low security. (Please refer Lecture 37@31:11, 32: 43, 32: 25)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank. ___ means independent of device or location.",
      "options": [
        "Scalable",
        "Reliability",
        "Agile",
        "Ubiquitous"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Ubiquitous",
      "solution": "Ubiquitous means independent of device or location. (Please refer Lecture 37@18:06)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank. ___ represents the on-demand delivery of computing infrastructure in the cloud.",
      "options": [
        "Software-as-a-Service",
        "Storage-as-a-Service",
        "Network-as-a-Service",
        "Infrastructure-as-a-Service"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Infrastructure-as-a-Service",
      "solution": "Infrastructure-as-a-Service represents the on-demand delivery of computing infrastructure in the cloud. (Please refer Lecture 38@4:29)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank. Hybrid cloud is a blend of ___ cloud.",
      "options": [
        "Public and private",
        "SaaS and Paas",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Public and private",
      "solution": "Hybrid cloud is a blend of public and private cloud. (Please refer Lecture 38@9:50)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Software-as-a-Service does not support a fully pay-as-you-go model.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "Software-as-a-Service supports a fully pay-as-you-go model. (Please refer Lecture 38@13:25)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following describes the quality of services expected by the customer?",
      "options": [
        "Mass production",
        "Internet evolution",
        "Automation",
        "Service Level Agreement"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Service Level Agreement",
      "solution": "Service Level Agreement describes the quality of services expected by the customer (Please refer Lecture 39@5:23)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are the accesses enabled by the access control layers in the cloud?",
      "options": [
        "Service access",
        "Server access",
        "Database access",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Service access, Server access and Database access are the accesses enabled by the access control layers in the cloud (Please refer Lecture 39@24:31)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Reputation refers to the belief of an entity's standing by the community.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "Reputation refers to the belief of an entity's standing by the community. (Please refer Lecture 39@25:15)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true about GreenCloud?",
      "options": [
        "GreenCloud monitors the energy consumption of servers, switches, etc.",
        "GreenCloud was developed as an extension of NS2.",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "GreenCloud monitors the energy consumption of servers, switches, etc. It was developed as an extension of NS2. (Please refer Lecture 40@16:25)"
    }
  ],
  "week9": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a component of OpenStack?",
      "options": [
        "Suse",
        "Nova",
        "Swift",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Suse",
      "solution": "Nova and Swift are two of the many components of OpenStack (Please refer Lecture 41@3:18)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Where is the sensed data sent for further processing in WSNs?",
      "options": [
        "Client node",
        "Central node",
        "Collect node",
        "Sink node"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Sink node",
      "solution": "The sensed data is sent to sink node for further processing in WSNs (Please refer Lecture 42@4:04)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Select the statement(s) that denote the advantages of cloud computing. Statement I: Elasticity Statement II: Pay-per-use Statement III: Self Service",
      "options": [
        "Statement I",
        "Statement II",
        "Statements I, II, and III",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Statements I, II, and III",
      "solution": "The advantages of cloud computing are Elasticity, pay-per-use and self service (Please refer Lecture 42@5:58)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a limitation of WSN?",
      "options": [
        "Price",
        "Post deployment maintenance",
        "Battery lifetime",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Price, post deployment maintenance and battery lifetime are the main limitations of WSN. (Please refer Lecture 42@11:01)"
    },
    {
      "question": "The managerial role is played by ___ in sensor-cloud architecture.",
      "options": [
        "End-users",
        "Sensor-Cloud Service Provider",
        "None of these",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Sensor-Cloud Service Provider",
      "solution": "Sensor-Cloud Service Provider plays the managerial role in sensor-cloud architecture. (Please refer Lecture 42@14:29)"
    },
    {
      "question": "The optimal composition of ___ is a management issue in sensor-cloud.",
      "options": [
        "Logistics",
        "Pricing",
        "Caching",
        "Virtual sensor nodes"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Virtual sensor nodes",
      "solution": "The optimal composition of Virtual sensor nodes is a management issue in sensor-cloud. (Please refer Lecture 43@4:39)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who coined the term Fog computing?",
      "options": [
        "IBM",
        "CISCO",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "CISCO",
      "solution": "CISCO coined the term Fog computing. (Please refer Lecture 44@4:18)"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the issues related to the current cloud model?",
      "options": [
        "Volume",
        "Latency",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Volume, bandwidth and latency are some of the issues related to the current cloud model. (Please refer Lecture 44@10:30)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Sensor data is processed in the cloud before it is sent to the fog.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "Sensor data is processed in the fog before it is sent to the cloud. (Please refer Lecture 45@6:11)"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the type of received data according to which Fog nodes work?.",
      "options": [
        "Non-time sensitive data",
        "Very time-sensitive data",
        "Less time-sensitive data",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Fog nodes work according to the type of data which are very time-sensitive, less time-sensitive and non-time sensitive data. (Please refer Lecture 45@11:39)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following are the advantages of Fog?",
      "options": [
        "Quick decision making",
        "Nodes can be mobile",
        "Reduces the risk of latency",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "The advantages of Fog includes quick decision making, nodes can be mobile and Fog reduces the risk of latency. (Please refer Lecture 45@20:57)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following requires the analysis at the nearest node?",
      "options": [
        "Non-time sensitive data",
        "Most time-sensitive data",
        "Less time-sensitive data",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Most time-sensitive data",
      "solution": "Most time-sensitive data requires the analysis at the nearest node. (Please refer Lecture 45@15:46)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fog nodes cannot connect and leave the network when necessary.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "Fog nodes can connect and leave the network when necessary. (Please refer Lecture 45@25:27)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is used by the fog applications to increase the speed of service accessibility?",
      "options": [
        "Low power",
        "Good network connection",
        "Accelerators",
        "Analytics"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Accelerators",
      "solution": "Accelerators increase the speed of service accessibility. (Please refer to Page 260, Chapter 11, Introduction to IoT...)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank. The concept of ___ enables physical hardware to be shared among multiple entities.",
      "options": [
        "Hardware virtualization",
        "Software virtualization",
        "Module virtualization",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Hardware virtualization",
      "solution": "The concept of hardware virtualization enables physical hardware to be shared among multiple entities. (Please refer to Page 262, Chapter 11, Introduction to IoT...)"
    }
  ],
  "week10": [
    {
      "question": "Smart homes can be used for",
      "options": [
        "Home monitoring",
        "Conservation of resources like electricity",
        "Security and safety",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Smart homes can be used for home monitoring, conservation of resources, security and safety. (Please refer Lecture 46@25:02)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an iot challenge in smart cities?",
      "options": [
        "Reliability",
        "Large scale",
        "Big data",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Reliability, Large scale and Big data are some of the challenges of iot in smart cities. (Please refer Lecture 46@32:57)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Select the statement(s) that are true for smart parking. Statement I: Smart parking reduces traffic congestion Statement II: Smart parking increases urban mobility Statement III: Smart parking reduces fuel consumption",
      "options": [
        "Statement I",
        "Statement II",
        "Statements I, II, and III",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Statements I, II, and III",
      "solution": "Smart parking reduces traffic congestion and fuel consumption, and increases urban mobility (Please refer Lecture 47@16:46)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a functional layer in smart parking?",
      "options": [
        "Information Collection",
        "System Deployment",
        "Service Dissemination",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Information Collection, System Deployment and Service Dissemination are all the functional layers in smart parking. (Please refer Lecture 47@17:24)"
    },
    {
      "question": "The mobile sensing in smart parking collects the information",
      "options": [
        "in-place",
        "along the route",
        "None of these",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "along the route",
      "solution": "The mobile sensing in smart parking collects the information along the route. (Please refer Lecture 47@19:47)"
    },
    {
      "question": "The network which provides amalgamation of various systems within a home is known as",
      "options": [
        "Local Area Network",
        "Metropolitan Area Network",
        "Global Area Network",
        "Home Area Network"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Home Area Network",
      "solution": "The network which provides amalgamation of various systems within a home is known as Home Area Network. (Please refer Lecture 48@8:24)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the correct full form of DLNA Standards for HAN?",
      "options": [
        "Digital Lifestyle Network Alliance",
        "Digital Living Network Alliance",
        "Digital Lifestyle Network Algorithm",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Digital Living Network Alliance",
      "solution": "DLNA stands for Digital Living Network Alliance standards. (Please refer Lecture 48@13:49)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a part of ZigBee Alliance?",
      "options": [
        "Mitsubishi",
        "Honeywell",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "The Zigbee Alliance is composed of Mitsubishi, Honeywell, Invensys, Motorola and Philips. (Please refer Lecture 48@15:46)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Network and Application layers are defined by IEEE 802.15.4 in Zigbee.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "Network and Application layers are defined by Zigbee in Zigbee. (Please refer Lecture 48@16:42)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a feature of Content Centric Networking?",
      "options": [
        "Hierarchically named data",
        "Scalable data dissemination",
        "In-network caching",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Hierarchically named data, Scalable data dissemination and In-network caching are all the features of CCN. (Please refer Lecture 49@15:17)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a phase of ICV development?",
      "options": [
        "Based on 2G",
        "Based on 4G LTE",
        "Vehicles connected to cloud",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "The phases of ICV development: Phase 1: Based on 2G, Phase 2: Based on 4G LTE, Phase 3: Vehicles connected to cloud (Please refer Lecture 50@12:28)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a property of V2X?",
      "options": [
        "Restricted to a single source",
        "Distributed architecture",
        "Both of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Distributed architecture",
      "solution": "V2X follows a distributed architecture. (Please refer Lecture 49@12:06)"
    },
    {
      "question": "The vehicles cannot be mobile in the Ad-hoc domain of VANET.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "The vehicles are mobile in the Ad-hoc domain of VANET.. (Please refer Lecture 50@16:59)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a domain of VANET?",
      "options": [
        "In-vehicle",
        "Ad-hoc",
        "All of these",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Both of the In-vehicle and Ad-hoc are the two domains of VANETS. (Please refer Lecture 50@14:36)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank. ICV is based on",
      "options": [
        "Dedicated Short Range Communication",
        "Directed Short Range Communication",
        "Dedicated Small Range Communication",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Dedicated Short Range Communication",
      "solution": "ICV is based on Dedicated Short Range Communication. (Please refer Lecture 50@7:22)"
    }
  ],
  "week11": [
    {
      "question": "What are some of the other names of the smart grids?",
      "options": [
        "Electricity with a brain",
        "Energybar",
        "Electrolyte",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Electricity with a brain",
      "solution": "Smart grids are also known as Electricity with a brain, Energy internet, and Electronet. (Please refer Lecture 51@8:33)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Traditional Grid follows which type of flow of energy?",
      "options": [
        "Unidirectional",
        "Bidirectional",
        "Both a and b",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Unidirectional",
      "solution": "Traditional grid follows unidirectional flow of energy. (Please refer Lecture 51@5:41)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a benefit associated with smart grids?",
      "options": [
        "Efficient transmission of electricity",
        "Lower electricity rates",
        "Improved security",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Smart Grids provide efficient transmission of electricity, lower electricity rates and Improved security. (Please refer Lecture 51@11:26)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a way of consumer engagement?",
      "options": [
        "Net metering",
        "Time-of-Use pricing",
        "Financial incentives",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Net metering, Time-of-Use pricing and Financial incentives are ways of consumer engagements. (Please refer Lecture 51 @32:31)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank. In ___, a home can have power from distributed resources.",
      "options": [
        "Peaking",
        "Islanding",
        "Neither a nor b",
        "Both a and b"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Islanding",
      "solution": "In islanding, a home can have power from distributed resources. (Please refer Lecture 51 @31:20)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following aggregates energy consumption of a certain geographical area?",
      "options": [
        "Data Aggregator Units",
        "Meter Data Management System",
        "Buffer",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Data Aggregator Units",
      "solution": "Data Aggregator Units aggregates energy consumption of a certain geographical area (Please refer Lecture 52@15:03)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following statements are true about Dynamic System Attacks? Statement I: Replay attacks compromises sensors and monitors their outputs. Statement II: D-DIA can lead to a system collapse. Statement III: Covert attack is a closed loop version of replay attacks.",
      "options": [
        "Statements I and II",
        "Statements I and III",
        "Statements II and III",
        "Statement I, II and III"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Statement I, II and III",
      "solution": "Replay attacks compromises sensors and monitors their outputs. D-DIA can lead to a system collapse. Covert attack is a closed loop version of replay attacks. (Please refer Lecture 52@20:03)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank. ___ is a centralized coordinator for smart grid communication.",
      "options": [
        "Gateway",
        "Meter",
        "AMI",
        "MDMS"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "MDMS",
      "solution": "MDMS is a centralized coordinator for smart grid communication. (Please refer Lecture 52@15:32)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank. ___ are available protocols for smart home appliances.",
      "options": [
        "C-Bus",
        "DECT",
        "EnOcean",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "C-Bus, DECT, EnOcean and Universal Powerline Bus are available protocols for smart home appliances. (Please refer Lecture 52@ 12:35)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank. ___ is the time required to transmit the data.",
      "options": [
        "Scalability",
        "Topology",
        "Throughput",
        "Latency"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Latency",
      "solution": "Latency is the time required to transmit the data. (Please refer Lecture 53@21:20)"
    },
    {
      "question": "IIoT is based on Wrap & Replace approach.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "IIoT is based on wrap & re-use approach. (Please refer Lecture 53@9:53)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following happened in the 3rd Revolution?",
      "options": [
        "Mass production",
        "IIoT",
        "Mechanized production",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "None of these",
      "solution": "Internet evolution and automation happened in the 3rd Revolution. (Please refer Lecture 53@10:06)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is used to improve the interoperability of different systems?",
      "options": [
        "Standardization",
        "Optimization",
        "Monitoring",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Standardization",
      "solution": "Standardization improves the interoperability of different systems. (Please refer Lecture 54@16:09)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Big data is characterized by 7 Vs.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "Big data is characterized by 7 Vs. (Please refer Lecture 55@10:36)"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Hadoop used in?",
      "options": [
        "Distributed processing of large datasets",
        "Small clusters of computers",
        "Both a and b",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Distributed processing of large datasets",
      "solution": "Hadoop is used for distributed processing of large datasets across Large clusters of computers (Please refer Lecture 55@23:18)"
    }
  ],
  "week12": [
    {
      "question": "The two types of data analysis are",
      "options": [
        "Qualitative and Quantitative",
        "Repetitive and Quantitative",
        "Neither a nor b",
        "Both a and b"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Qualitative and Quantitative",
      "solution": "Qualitative and Quantitative are the two types of data analysis. (Please refer Lecture 56@2:33)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a principle of Qualitative analysis.",
      "options": [
        "Notice things",
        "Think about things",
        "Collect things",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "The three principles of Qualitative analysis are: Notice things, think about things and collect things. (Please refer Lecture 56@4:12)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Select the statement(s) that is involved with quantitative analysis. Statement I: Data dispersion Statement II: Contingence Statement III: Correlation",
      "options": [
        "Statement I",
        "Statement II",
        "Statements I, II, and III",
        "None of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Statements I, II, and III",
      "solution": "Data dispersion, Contingence and Correlation are involved with quantitative analysis. (Please refer Lecture 56@4:46)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a type of data dispersion?",
      "options": [
        "Range",
        "Average absolute deviation",
        "Both a and b",
        "Neither a nor b"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Both a and b",
      "solution": "Range and average absolute deviation are the type of data dispersions. (Please refer Lecture 56@13:43)"
    },
    {
      "question": "In ANOVA, if the distribution of each group is normal, it is known as",
      "options": [
        "Homogeneity",
        "Normality",
        "Neither a nor b",
        "Both a and b"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Normality",
      "solution": "In ANOVA, if the distribution of each group is normal, it is known as normality. (Please refer Lecture 56@11:01)"
    },
    {
      "question": "The expectation of the squared deviation of a random variable from its mean is known as",
      "options": [
        "Absolute deviation",
        "Range",
        "Standard deviation",
        "Variance"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Variance",
      "solution": "The expectation of the squared deviation of a random variable from its mean is known as Variance. (Please refer Lecture 56@14:04)"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the two types of statistical models?",
      "options": [
        "Regression and dispersion",
        "Complete and incomplete",
        "Both a and b",
        "Neither a nor b"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Complete and incomplete",
      "solution": "Complete and incomplete are two types of statistical models (Please refer Lecture 56@8:11)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a type of table that displays the frequency distribution of the variables?",
      "options": [
        "Cross tabulation",
        "Contingency table",
        "Both a and b",
        "Neither a nor b"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Both a and b",
      "solution": "Contingency table is a type of table that displays the frequency distribution of the variables. It is also known as Cross tabulation and Cross tab. (Please refer Lecture 56@14:29)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Advances in sensor and connectivity have enabled preventive care in IoT Healthcare.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "True",
      "solution": "Advances in sensor and connectivity have enabled preventive care in IoT Healthcare. (Please refer Lecture 58@4:22)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an application of IoT in Agriculture?.",
      "options": [
        "Automated irrigation system",
        "Automated weeding system",
        "Water level monitoring",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Automated irrigation system, Automated weeding system and Water level monitoring are all applications of IoT in agriculture. (Please refer Lecture 57@2:05)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a property of in-place data analysis?",
      "options": [
        "Power intensive",
        "On the device",
        "No need of network",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "In-place data analysis is power intensive, can be done on the device and needs no network connection. (Please refer Lecture 59@20:24)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is the advantage of activity monitoring?",
      "options": [
        "Expensive",
        "Long term monitoring",
        "Both a and b",
        "Neither a nor b"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Long term monitoring",
      "solution": "Long term monitoring is one of the advantages of Activity monitoring. (Please refer Lecture 59@16:17)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Deep learning based data analysis cannot be performed on sensor data.",
      "options": [
        "True",
        "False"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "False",
      "solution": "Deep learning based data analysis can be done on sensor data, images and videos. (Please refer Lecture 59@19:34)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is true for network-based data analysis?",
      "options": [
        "Low power",
        "Good network connection required",
        "Group-based analytics",
        "All of these"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "All of these",
      "solution": "Network-based data analysis uses low power, good network connection and can perform group-based analytics (Please refer Lecture 59@20:10)"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an advantage of continuous activity monitoring?",
      "options": [
        "Daily observation of behavior",
        "Long term monitoring",
        "Neither a nor b",
        "Both a and b"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Both a and b",
      "solution": "Daily observation of behavior and Long term monitoring are two advantages of continuous activity monitoring. (Please refer Lecture 59@16:15)"
    }
  ]
}